export const CLOTHINGTEXTILESA2023 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A safety measure taken when sewing by hand is to use",
A: "magnet.",
B: "pin cushion.",
C: "thumb pin.",
D: "thimble.",
answer: "D. thimble.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Bes The most important activity carried out in the clothing laboratory is",
A: "sewing.",
B: "fitting.",
C: "modelling.",
D: "drafting. '",
answer: "A. sewing.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. In order to look well groomed, it is advisable to wear",
A: "clothes in vogue always.",
B: "smile on your face always.",
C: "expensive accessories to match outer garment.",
D: "high heeled shoes for every important occasion.",
answer: "B. smile on your face always.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Measurement required for determining figure type include",
A: "neck measurement.",
B: "bust measurement.",
C: "height measurement.",
D: "waist measurement.",
answer: "C. height measurement.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The best tape measure for garment making is",
A: "metal tape.",
B: "plastic tape.",
C: "pliable tape.",
D: "meter rule,",
answer: "C. pliable tape.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. An a example ofa silk fabric is",
A: "crepe.",
B: "chintz.",
C: "serge.",
D: "damask.",
answer: "A. crepe.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The best seam to use on fabric that frays easily is",
A: "plain seam.",
B: "overlaid seam.",
C: "French seam.",
D: "welt seam.",
answer: "C. French seam.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Alteration in garment should be made before washing in order to prevent",
A: "the garment from getting dirty.",
B: "stitched holes from showing.",
C: "fabric from fading.",
D: "seams from showing.",
answer: "B. stitched holes from showing.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Examples of figure types include",
A: "tall and huge figure.",
B: "tall and thin figure.",
C: "slim and thin figure.",
D: "bulky and short figure.",
answer: "B. tall and thin figure.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Fibres that have high rate of absorbency are",
A: "protein and mineral fibres.",
B: "cellulosic and synthetic fibres.",
C: "protein and cellulosic fibres.",
D: "polyester and synthetic fibres.",
answer: "C. protein and cellulosic fibres.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. In garment construction, which of the following fabric will need extra quantity?",
A: "Slippery fabrics",
B: "Stripped fabrics",
C: "Stretchy fabrics",
D: "Coarse fabrics",
answer: "B. Stripped fabrics.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The main reason for organizing fashion show is to",
A: "enhance designer’s image.",
B: "evaluate product patronage.",
C: "compete with others.",
D: "Toms entertain the crowd.",
answer: "A. enhance designer’s image.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. An itinerant enterprise involves",
A: "selling habadashery,",
B: "clothing alteration services.",
C: "dressmaking services.",
D: "a fabric printing house.",
answer: "A. selling haberdashery.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Some accessories that Clothing and Textiles students can produce for sale are",
A: "soft toys, armrest and hairband.",
B: "wristband, necklace and curtain rings.",
C: "hat, jewellery and tablemats.",
D: "hairband, earrings and footwear.",
answer: "D. hairband, earrings, and footwear.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. To be self-employed in the clothing industry implies",
A: "setting up and employing workers.",
B: "creating business for others.",
C: "setting up and managing business.",
D: "depending on others for one’s business.",
answer: "C. setting up and managing business.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. When fixing hook and eye during garment making, the metal bar is sewn to the",
A: "wrong side of the under wrap.",
B: "right side of the overlap.",
C: "wrong side of the over wrap.",
D: "right side of the under wrap.",
answer: "B. right side of the overlap.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Perspiration stain is best removed by",
A: "brine.",
B: "ammonia.",
C: "methylated spirit.",
D: "borax solution.",
answer: "D. borax solution.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Good grooming practices include:\nI. wearing very expensive clothing\nIl. maintaining good posture\nIll. bleaching the body\nIV. adequate rest and relaxation.",
A: "I, II and III only",
B: "IL, II and IV only",
C: "III and IV only",
D: "II and IV only",
answer: "B. II, II, and IV only.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Cotton linters mixed with chemicals will produce",
A: "polymers.",
B: "polyamide.",
C: "acrylic.",
D: "rayon.",
answer: "D. rayon.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A pair of scissors that can be substituted for cutting buttonholes is",
A: "cutting out scissors.",
B: "embroidery scissors.",
C: "small scissors.",
D: "pinking shears.",
answer: "B. embroidery scissors.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The grease obtained from raw wool is known as",
A: "cystin.",
B: "lanolin.",
C: "keratin.",
D: "medulla.",
answer: "B. lanolin.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Regenerated fibres are manufactured from",
A: "cellulosic fibres and chemicals.",
B: "vegetable and modified fibres.",
C: "minerals and chemicals.",
D: "natural fibres and chemicals.",
answer: "A. cellulosic fibres and chemicals.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. One of the characteristics of knitted fabric is that it is",
A: "stretchy.",
B: "lustrous.",
C: "coarse.",
D: "bulky.",
answer: "A. stretchy.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Rouleaux loops are suitable fastenings for openings",
A: "which overlap. ,",
B: "which meet at the edges.",
C: "that are bound.",
D: "that are faced.",
answer: "A. which overlap.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. During burning test a fibre which is found to burn slowly and smells like burning hair is",
A: "cotton.",
B: "wool.",
C: "linen.",
D: "acrylic.",
answer: "B. wool.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The finished end of a vertical buttonholes are,",
A: "round.",
B: "zig-zag.",
C: "square.",
D: "straight.",
answer: "C. square.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The amount of fabric required for the width of a pleat is",
A: "three times the width.",
B: "two and half times the width.",
C: "two times the width.",
D: "one and half times the width.",
answer: "A. three times the width.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. In Clothing and Textiles, asbestos fibre is used to produce",
A: "ironing stand.",
B: "ironing table.",
C: "heat resistant mat.",
D: "dress form.",
answer: "C. heat resistant mat.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. To remove fresh mud stain from an article,",
A: "steep in warm water, wash and dry in the sun.",
B: "dry stain completely, brush off caked mud and launder.",
C: "dry stain completely, wash and dry.",
D: "scrape the mud and wash.",
answer: "B. dry stain completely, brush off caked mud and launder.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The correct sitting position include",
A: "crossing the leg above the knee.",
B: "sitting straight with the stomach protruding.",
C: "sitting with legs apart.",
D: "sitting with knees in line with hip.",
answer: "D. sitting with knees in line with hip.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. One advantage of freehand cutting is that,",
A: "instructions are available.",
B: "unique designs are developed.",
C: "very few steps are involved.",
D: "is convenient for all categories of people.",
answer: "B. unique designs are developed.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. A strong and flat method of repairing articles which require frequent washing is",
A: "calico patch.",
B: "print patch.",
C: "hand darning.",
D: "hole darning.",
answer: "A. calico patch.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. The machine hccessories used for making gathers is known as",
A: "quilter.",
B: "binder.",
C: "hemmer.",
D: "ruffle.",
answer: "D. ruffle.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Mineral fabrics are used for",
A: "drapery and upholstery.",
B: "protective clothing.",
C: "garment and accessories.",
D: "ladies undergarment.",
answer: "B. protective clothing.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Interlacing the same number of warp yams with the same number of weft yarns form a",
A: "plain weave.",
B: "rib weave.",
C: "satin weave.",
D: "twill weave.",
answer: "A. plain weave.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Under the microscope, cotton fibre looks like",
A: "flat twisted ribbon.",
B: "curly lustrous ribbon.",
C: "smooth solid rod.",
D: "scaly cylindrical rod.",
answer: "A. flat twisted ribbon.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The fit of a garment depends on the",
A: "quantity of fabric used.",
B: "skills of the worker.",
C: "texture of fabric.",
D: "trimmings used.",
answer: "B. skills of the worker.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The purpose of wearing a full slip is to make the outer garment",
A: "hang well.",
B: "opaque.",
C: "on look attractive.",
D: "durable.",
answer: "A. hang well.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. An example of machine attachment is",
A: "pressure bar.",
B: "spool pin,",
C: "bobbin.",
D: "binder.",
answer: "D. binder.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The most effective tool for unpicking stitches is",
A: "small scissors.",
B: "seam ripper. .",
C: "blade. k",
D: "pin. :",
answer: "B. seam ripper.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. To regulate the tightness and looseness of stitches on the sewing machine, adjust the",
A: "tension disc.",
B: "stitch regulator.",
C: "needle position selector.",
D: "pressure regulator.",
answer: "A. tension disc.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Fabrics which can be heat-set into shape are described as being",
A: "thermoplastic.",
B: "trubernized.",
C: "polymerized.",
D: "elastomeric.",
answer: "A. thermoplastic.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The type of fullness that are usually introduced into men’s trousers aie",
A: "gathers and pleats.",
B: "tucks:and pleats.",
C: "gathers and tucks.",
D: "pleats and-darts,",
answer: "D. pleats and darts.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The most important reason for inserting a gusset into the underarm of a sleeve is to",
A: "give free movement.",
B: "create design.",
C: "provide space.",
D: "introduce extra width.",
answer: "A. give free movement.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Rust stain on a garment is removed by using",
A: "oxalic acid.",
B: "tomato juice.",
C: "lemon juice.",
D: "acetic acid.",
answer: "A. oxalic acid.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. For effective result smocking requires",
A: "three times the finished width of fabric.",
B: "twice the finished length of fabric.",
C: "four times the finished length of fabric.",
D: "twice the finished width of fabric.",
answer: "D. twice the finished width of fabric.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. The part labelled I represents",
A: "line.",
B: "proportion.",
C: "texture.",
D: "balance.",
answer: "A. line.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The part labelled I indicates the principle of design known as",
A: "shape.",
B: "balance.",
C: "harmony.",
D: "proportion.",
answer: "B. balance.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The part labelled IMJ, IV, and V represents",
A: "balance.",
B: "proportion.",
C: "emphasis.",
D: "contrast.",
answer: "D. contrast.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Factors to consider in order to promote success in a Clothing and Textiles enterprise include",
A: "hard work and commitment.",
B: "securing loan for equipment.",
C: "good rapport with some clients.",
D: "flexibility in providing credit facilities.",
answer: "A. hard work and commitment.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question51",
question:  "51. The best stitch to use when attaching press studs to garment is",
A: "stern stitch.",
B: "buttonhole stitch.",
C: "hemming stitch.",
D: "overcasting stitch.",
answer: "C. hemming stitch.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question52",
question:  "52. Identification of fibres is done by",
A: "feeling the fabric.",
B: "viewing under the microscope.",
C: "applying alkaline solution.",
D: "using chlorine solution.",
answer: "B. viewing under the microscope.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question53",
question:  "53. Garment worn next to the skin to help maintain the shape of the body are known as",
A: "leggings.",
B: "lingerie.",
C: "foundation garments.",
D: "inner garments.",
answer: "C. foundation garments.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question54",
question:  "54. A collar that stands on the neck of a garment can be described as",
A: "shaw! collar.",
B: "mandarin collar.",
C: "sailor collar.",
D: "Eton collar.",
answer: "B. mandarin collar.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question55",
question:  "55. The neckline of a toddler’s sleep wear is best neatened by",
A: "using rolled edge and shell edging.",
B: "attaching band.",
C: "using shaped facing and binding.",
D: "turning a hem.",
answer: "C. using shaped facing and binding.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question56",
question:  "56. The most important reason for drying white bedsheet in the sun is the",
A: "bleaching effect.",
B: "removal of soap scent.",
C: "the freshness it derives.",
D: "quick drying process.",
answer: "A. bleaching effect.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question57",
question:  "57. In wardrobe planning money can be saved if outgrown garments are",
A: "remodeled and given out.",
B: "renovated and stored well.",
C: "renovated or remodeled,",
D: "remodeled and used.",
answer: "C. renovated or remodeled.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question58",
question:  "58. A sleeve set into the bodice from the underarm to the neckline is",
A: "puff sleeve.",
B: "raglan sleeve.",
C: "magyar sleeve.",
D: "cape sleeve.",
answer: "B. raglan sleeve.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question59",
question:  "59. The most important factor in wardrobe planning is",
A: "one’s identity.",
B: "the family’s income.",
C: "the number of people.",
D: "occupation of family members.",
answer: "B. the family’s income.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question60",
question:  "60. Factors that promote good grooming include",
A: "dressing in conformity with peers.",
B: "wearing fashionable clothing.",
C: "maintaining cleanliness.",
D: "wearing clothes in vogue.",
answer: "C. maintaining cleanliness.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]